

JOLSNA V JOSE

918075543422

iolsna.hr@gmail.com

 iolsna.hr@gmail.com

Bangalore, India

inkedin.com/in/jolsna-v-jose-5a61b48b/

PROFILE

Dedicated professional with proven skills and experience in recruiting, staffing, vendor management and human resource management. Dependable with proven ability to succeed under pressure, deliver excellence, establish genuine and relationships. A team player with effective interpersonal communication skills and a strong work ethic. Four years of experience in Recruitment working with domain clients like Software, Financial, Telecom, and Banking. Successful in Sourcing, Screening, Validating, Salary Negotiation and Placement follow-up.

KEY SKILLS

- □ Proficient in ATS
- □ Talent Management
- □ Staff Recruitment & Retention
- □ Employee Relations
- □ Alternative Dispute Resolutions
- □ Orientation &Onboarding
- □ Training & Development
- □ Performance Management
- □ Organizational Development
- □ Oral & Written Communication
- ☐ MS Office (Word, Excel)Tally ERP

EDUCATION

- MBA in Human Resource & Marketing, Kannur
 University, Kerala, India-2013
- MSW in Medical & Psychiatry,
 M G University, Kerala, India-2010
- □ BSc Science, Kannur University, Kerala, India-2008

LANGUAGES

- □ Tamil
- Malayalam

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 $\textbf{Syban India: Global HR Services Provider} - \textbf{Bangalore}, \textbf{India} \ (05/2023-07/2023)$

Recruitment Consultant

Syban India: Global HR Services Provider – Bangalore, India. (07/2021 – 07/2022)

Aquity Solutions India Pvt Ltd-Bangalore, India. (08/2019 -09/2020)

HR Executive

Mansard Software Soluions Pvt Ltd –Bangalore, India. (1/2018 -08/2019)

HR Recruiter

Ultraline Logistics & Freight Services- Doha , Qatar. $(01/2016-10/2016)\,$

HR Executive

WORK EXPERIENCE

Recruiter (IT & Automotive)

Syban India: Global HR Services Provider-Bangalore, India

07/2021 - 07/2023

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Coordinating with hiring managers to identify staffing needs/Vacancy intake.
- Full cycle recruitment process from creating job descriptions, determining sourcing channels, screening, interview process, providing feedback to the candidates, offer acceptance, negotiations and on-boarding.
- Plan interview and selection procedures, including screening calls, assessments and in-person interviews for Automotive industry (OEM).
- Utilized advanced Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS) such as Procure Wise, Vultus Recruit, etc. to streamline recruitment processes and improve candidate management.
- Design job descriptions and interview questions that reflect each position's requirements.
- Sourcing potential candidates through online channels (e.g., social platforms and professional networks).
- · Checking existing talent pool and employee referrals.
- Identifying the best talent, and analyzing each resume carefully, paying attention to the detail.
- · Conducting screening interview to weed out incompatible job applicants.
- Coordinating with hiring manager other team members to develop a successful recruitment function.
- Supporting hiring manager in making a data driven hiring decision.
- · Providing feedback to the candidates.
- Keeping in touch with new hires during pre boarding period to keep them engaged and excited to get started.
- · Documentation of the new hires.
- · Regularly checks in with the new employee while on boarding.

Skills worked for Automotive: Senior Configuration Engineer – Electromobility, System Design Engineer (Lead & Senior), Hardware Engineer (Senior& Junior), GM BMS-Electromobility, GM OppCharge Power Conversion, GM Software Cl/CD, GM ESS Control, Geometrical Architect - Virtual Builds, Verification Engineer (Senior & Lead) Epic Owner – Driver Security, Safety & Visibility, Senior Engineer- Crash & Safety, Engineer – Durability, Engineer – Aerodynamics, Soiling, Aero-Acoustics, Thermal Managemen, Lead ESW Integration, Material Controller, Transport Developer, SAP FICO, MS Dynamics CRM 365 etc.

Aguity Solutions India Pvt Ltd - Bangalore, India 08/2019 - 09/2020

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- · Recruitment and selection of candidates for interviews.
- Conduct pre- employment / reference checks for the experienced candidates who have been selected through the interview process.
- Liaison with team for Employee-Referral initiatives.
- Handles all on boarding and off boarding activities.
- Preparation of relevant letters to effect staff movements (appointment, resignation, transfers, confirmation and promotion)
- Scheduling induction and conduct the Induction programme.
- Monitor process compliance of team members.
- Administer HRIS system and updating employee employment records: hiring, transfer, promotion and Resignation.
- Taking care of Employee engagement activities and birthday celebration.
- Preparing weekly and monthly recruitment reports.
- Maintain the personal folders.
- Taking care of OU movement in respect to Departmental and Reporting changes.
- Handles employees Medical Insurance and claims processing.
- Interact with employees on a regular basis and maintain good employee relations.
- Preparation and initiate activities for the expansion of employee data bank.

HR Recruiter (IT & NON-IT)

Mansard Software Solutions Pvt Ltd -Bangalore, India

1/2018- 08/2019

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Sourcing of candidates through job portals, candidate's references, and internal data.
- Working closely with Hiring Managers/Project Managers to get detailed requirements along with meeting the deadlines for submissions of per requirements.
- Responsible for creating job postings, reviewing a high volume of resumes, conducting telephonic interviews, coordinating interviews with the clients, extending offers, negotiating salary and follow up and closing the positions.
- Evaluating the candidate's Communication skill, Reason for Job Change, Work experience, present and expected compensation, location/relocation information, work authorization status, Notice Period, availability for the interview
- Attend standup meetings to update and discuss the Recruitment activities with the Recruitment Manager and plan the strategies to fulfill the roles.
- Worked on profiles ranging from entry levels to mid seniors levels.
- Taking regular feedback from the clients.

Skills worked for: Java/J2EE developer, C++ developer, .Net developer, Automation Testing, Mobile Application Testing, UI Developer, AWS Developer, Manual Testing, Software developer.



HR Executive

Ultraline Logistics & Freight Services - Doha, Qatar

01/2016 - 10/2016

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Perform and/or direct day to day administrative tasks.
- Maintain and file all records in accordance with company procedure.
- · Responsible to create HR policies and procedures with senior management.
- · Confer with management and staff coordinating all the activities.
- Ensure to process orders and on-time delivery of all the shipments to companies.
- Providing an enabling workplace by effective and timely resolution of employee grievances.
- Ensuring compliance to policies & code of conduct by the employees.
- Conducting induction and orientation programs for new joiners